<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cgMDR:cgDatatype xmlns:cgMDR="http://www.cancergrid.org/schema/cgMDR" datatype_identifier="DOENTJ350">
    <cgMDR:datatype_annotation/>
    <cgMDR:datatype_description>The ·value space· of date consists of top-open intervals of exactly
    one day in length on the timelines of dateTime, beginning on the beginning moment of each day
    (in each timezone), i.e. '00:00:00', up to but not including '24:00:00' (which is identical with
    '00:00:00' of the next day). For nontimezoned values, the top-open intervals disjointly cover
    the nontimezoned timeline, one per day. For timezoned values, the intervals begin at every
    minute and therefore overlap. A "date object" is an object with year, month, and day properties
    just like those of dateTime objects, plus an optional timezone-valued timezone property. (As
    with values of dateTime timezones are a special case of durations.) Just as a dateTime object
    corresponds to a point on one of the timelines, a date object corresponds to an interval on one
    of the two timelines as just described. Timezoned date values track the starting moment of their
    day, as determined by their timezone; said timezone is generally recoverable for canonical
    representations. [Definition:] The recoverable timezone is that duration which is the result of
    subtracting the first moment (or any moment) of the timezoned date from the first moment (or the
    corresponding moment) UTC on the same date. ·recoverable timezone·s are always durations between
    '+12:00' and '-11:59'. This "timezone normalization" (which follows automatically from the
    definition of the date ·value space·) is explained more in Lexical representation (§3.2.9.1).
    For example: the first moment of 2002-10-10+13:00 is 2002-10-10T00:00:00+13, which is
    2002-10-09T11:00:00Z, which is also the first moment of 2002-10-09-11:00. Therefore
    2002-10-10+13:00 is 2002-10-09-11:00; they are the same interval.</cgMDR:datatype_description>
    <cgMDR:datatype_name>xs:date</cgMDR:datatype_name>
    <cgMDR:datatype_scheme_reference>XMLSchema</cgMDR:datatype_scheme_reference>
</cgMDR:cgDatatype>